720-785-0488 rarothsc@gmail.com rarothschild.github.io/RobSite2/



Robert Rothschild

OBJECTIVE

Over the last few years of engineering I've found that the parts I enjoyed most has been the software engineering aspects. I would like to find find a job that allows me to exercise my strength and knowledge from engineering and apply it to the new software engineering techniques I have been teaching myself.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Engineering

2014 - 2018

Fort Lewis College, Durango, CO

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer - Self Taught

May 2022 - Current

- Built full stack applications using tools such as Django, React JS, Solid JS and other common development tools.
- Familiar with all aspects of application development, including user authentication, database management, and deployment.
- Github: github.com/rarothschild

Engineer - The Heliospace Corporation

2017 - 2022

- Created a Matlab API to handle large sets of FEA data. This includes the file management, post processing, and result presentation.
- Managed databases for Bills of Material, Materials Identification and Usage Lists across multiple projects.
- Authored and contributed to many technical documents that were delivered to customers, including test and analysis reports.
- Provided oversight during integration and testing of the James Webb Space Telescope as well as Systems Engineering services. In addition, provided verification and validation on observatory requirements.
- Designed hardware for both NASA's Lunar Gateway and Mars Sample Return missions.

Researcher - Colorado Space Grant Consortium

2016 - 2018

- Designed, fabricated, and programmed a robot capable of autonomously traversing desert environments.
- Collected astronomical images using Fort Lewis' observatory.

Research Assistant - Fort Lewis College

2015

- Operated an autonomous boat to collect various scientific data.
- Processed this data into results used in publication.

RELEVANT PROGRAMMING KNOWLEDGE

Django

Python

HTML

CSS

GCP

 MatLab

LaTeX

MS Office













LATEX



PUBLICATIONS

S.-H. Yoo, A. Stuntz, Y. Zhang, R. Rothschild, G. A. Hollinger, and R. N. Smith, "Experimental analysis of receding horizon planning for marine monitoring," in Proceedings of The 10th International Conference on Field and Service Robotics, (Toronto, Canada), June 2015.

REFERENCES

Available upon request, since this resume is public I'd like to hide their personal details.